<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Gendering men: implications for gender equality]]></title>
		<theme><![CDATA[Gender equality]]></theme>
		<region><![CDATA[Global]]></region>
		<date><![CDATA[2006]]></date>
		<authors><![CDATA[Pease, B]]></authors>
		<publisher><![CDATA[Ministry of Social Affairs and Health]]></publisher>
		<uri><![CDATA[http://www.verwey-jonker.nl/doc/participatie/3590_PDF.pdf]]></uri>
		<dcoumenttype><![CDATA[Paper]]></dcoumenttype>
		<summarylink><![CDATA[http://menandboys.ids.ac.uk/files/gendering-men-implications-gender-equality?vnc=8MjUJ-j48MOZk6ucA5g475GU1335TCR6vJVfrCvmo9A&vnp=4]]></summarylink>
		<description><![CDATA[What motivates men to support and promote gender equality? Can it only happen on the basis of altruism or do men have something to gain? For over thirty years gender politics have struggled to find answers to these questions. This paper provides an overview of the key debates on the relationship between men and gender mainstreaming. It argues that if gender is regarded to be essentially about women, then it is impossible to recognise the relational dimension of gender and the way that institutionally-based unequal power relations are reproduced. If gender is only about women, men?s gender identities are not being challenged and perceived as natural.

This paper also takes into account some of the negative impacts of gender mainstreaming by highlighting that women?s services have been cut to finance men?s services and that this has supported the men?s rights discourse about men as victims. Many feminists have hence been sceptical about the possibility for real alliances. At the same time, the paper argues that there can be collective interests. When gender inequality is perceived as an oppressive system that harms the wider society men are willing to support ethical principles related to social justice.]]></description>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Evolving Men: Initial Results from the International Men and Gender Equality Survey (IMAGES)]]></title>
		<theme><![CDATA[Gender equality]]></theme>
		<region><![CDATA[Global]]></region>
		<date><![CDATA[Jan 2011]]></date>
		<authors><![CDATA[Barker G.; Contreras J M.; Heilman B.; Singh A.; Verma R.]]></authors>
		<publisher><![CDATA[International Center for Research on Women and Instituto Promundo]]></publisher>
		<uri><![CDATA[http://www.promundo.org.br/en/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Evolving-Men-IMAGES-1.pdf]]></uri>
		<dcoumenttype><![CDATA[Paper]]></dcoumenttype>
		<summarylink><![CDATA[http://menandboys.ids.ac.uk/files/evolving-men-initial-results-international-men-and-gender-equality-survey-images?vnc=rwBY6UrSwepQeaANGU_m7y9SJYwAEFh5dp-5mOqvYSE&vnp=4]]></summarylink>
		<description><![CDATA[Are men evolving in their practices and attitudes related to gender equality? Changes in gender attitudes do seem to be happening as younger men and men with higher levels of education show more gender equitable attitudes and practices. The evidence is presented in this report summarizes the initial, comparative analysis of The International Men and Gender Equality Survey (IMAGES). IMAGES is a comprehensive household questionnaire that surveyed men?s attitudes and practices ? along with women?s opinions and reports of men?s practices ? on topics related to gender equality. From 2009 to 2010, household surveys were administered to more than 8,000 men and 3,500 women ages 18-59 in Brazil, Chile, Croatia, India, Mexico and Rwanda. Topics in the questionnaire included: gender-based violence; health and health- related practices; household division of labour; men?s participation in caregiving and as fathers; men?s and women?s attitudes about gender and gender- related policies; transactional sex; men?s reports of criminal behaviour; and quality of life.

This initial report provides descriptive statistics and bi-variate analysis of key results for the topics listed above. IMAGES followed standard procedures for carrying out representative household surveys. The initial findings suggest that most men in the survey sites accept gender equality as an abstract even if they are not yet living it in their daily practices. This report is a useful resource for those wishing to implement policy and programming to promote gender equality.]]></description>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Marriage, Motherhood and Masculinity in the Global Economy: Reconfiguration of Personal and Economic Life]]></title>
		<theme><![CDATA[Marriage, motherhood and masculinities]]></theme>
		<region><![CDATA[Global]]></region>
		<date><![CDATA[Oct 2007]]></date>
		<authors><![CDATA[Kabeer, N.]]></authors>
		<publisher><![CDATA[IDS]]></publisher>
		<uri><![CDATA[http://www.ids.ac.uk/files/dmfile/Wp290.pdf]]></uri>
		<dcoumenttype><![CDATA[Paper]]></dcoumenttype>
		<summarylink><![CDATA[http://menandboys.ids.ac.uk/files/marriage-motherhood-and-masculinity-global-economy-reconfiguration-personal-and-economic-life]]></summarylink>
		<description><![CDATA[The informalisation and irregularity of work, and the feminisation of the global labour force are two critical outcomes of globalisation. What does the feminisation of the labour market mean for men and women?s experiences of gender equality?  Women?s increased access to work reflects multiple interrelated influences: shifts towards gender equity such as increased access to education for women and girls interact with deepening inequalities such as growing levels of landlessness and increased costs of living for all. Significantly this is happening in a context of stagnant and declining rates of male labour force participation. What do these changes mean in a context of a hegemonic masculinity, where men?s power is recognised through the identity of breadwinner?

This working paper establishes through an analysis of empirical studies that men have shown a stark refusal to share unpaid work within the household and that is reflected in local to global policy despite the growing importance of women?s income-generation responsibilities. Relatedly, demand for paid labour that until now was provided through women?s care roles within families and marriages has materialised. This includes both the unpaid workload of working women, and the commercial provision of companionship and sexual services. The evidence in this paper speaks to the ?crisis in masculinity? discourse, with men from poor and marginalised groups most affected in that they are furthest from the ideal of provider that underpins the dominant hegemony. One implication drawn from this analysis is that men?s involvement in care work may help to break down some of the rigidities of male identity and lessen their own vulnerability.]]></description>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Global Pathways to Men?s Caregiving: Mixed Methods Findings from the International Men and Gender Equality Survey and the Men Who Care Study]]></title>
		<theme><![CDATA[Mens caregiving; gender equality]]></theme>
		<region><![CDATA[Global]]></region>
		<date><![CDATA[June 2014]]></date>
		<authors><![CDATA[Kato-Wallace, J; Barker, G; Eads, M; Levtov, R]]></authors>
		<publisher><![CDATA[Global Public Health]]></publisher>
		<uri><![CDATA[http://www.promundo.org.br/en/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Global-Pathways-To-Mens-Caregiving_For-Website.pdf]]></uri>
		<dcoumenttype><![CDATA[Paper]]></dcoumenttype>
		<summarylink><![CDATA[http://menandboys.ids.ac.uk/files/global-pathways-men%E2%80%99s-caregiving-mixed-methods-findings-international-men-and-gender-equality?vnc=Dsh-O283bn7_7wYNx-xbKb0jigS01ckxywAEd-gE1fs&vnp=1]]></summarylink>
		<description><![CDATA[Promoting men?s participation in unpaid care work is an important step towards bringing about long-term sustainable gender equality. This study sought to understand the enabling childhood and adulthood factors that promote and encourage men?s involvement in caregiving. It uses quantitative research to present findings from?1169 men across six countries with children aged 0?4, and a qualitative study to present findings from in-depth interviews with 83 men engaged in atypical caregiving practices.

Data from this study suggests that men?s participation in care work is increasing, albeit at painfully slow rates. It found that being taught to?care?for children, witnessing one's father take?care?of one's siblings, respondents' present attitudes about?gender?equality?and having outside help (or in some cases, none) were associated with?men's?higher level of involvement. The resource recommends engaging men in the public health sector, and strengthening ?gender transformative? programme interventions in the areas of violence prevention and health promotion.]]></description>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Engaging men to prevent gender-based violence: A multi-country intervention and impact evaluation study]]></title>
		<theme><![CDATA[GBV]]></theme>
		<region><![CDATA[Chile, Brazil, India and Rwanda]]></region>
		<date><![CDATA[April 2012]]></date>
		<authors><![CDATA[Instituto Promundo]]></authors>
		<publisher><![CDATA[Instituto Promundo]]></publisher>
		<uri><![CDATA[http://www.promundo.org.br/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/UNT_Eng_10-1.pdf]]></uri>
		<dcoumenttype><![CDATA[Paper]]></dcoumenttype>
		<summarylink><![CDATA[http://menandboys.ids.ac.uk/files/engaging-men-prevent-gender-based-violence-multi-country-intervention-and-impact-evaluation?vnc=yD7taJ5A5NRy9K4fk4qhOjBAT3Sk57MiXQRGd7NFFL4&vnp=3]]></summarylink>
		<description><![CDATA[Assessing the impact of men?s engagement to prevent gender-based violence, and recognising good practices as they are developed is integral to the future of work to address gender inequalities and the violence that flows from power imbalances between men and women. This research shares the strategies for change implemented by, and the quasi-experimental impact evaluations of, four different three-year long projects to engage men to prevent gender-based violence in Chile, Brazil, India and Rwanda.  The research population group included men and women from ages 14-64. Themes of masculinity, gender, violence against women and sexuality were central to the efforts. All countries held a common intervention approach which included educational workshops with men on gender equity, campaigns and training programmes with partner staff on evidence-based methodologies for the prevention of violence against women.

In India, workshops were used to promote gender equality through the local leadership council, Panchayats. A decline in self-reported intimate-partner violence (IPV) and an increase in knowledge of laws around violence against women were recorded.
In Brazil, awareness about violence against women was raised by engaging men in dialogue through sports. There was a significant decrease in the percentage of men who accepted IPV and self-reported increase in conversations about gender equality.
In Chile, educational workshops were conducted for young men via the public health sector. Results showed a significant positive change in participants? self-reported behaviour towards greater gender equity, including an increase in condom use. 
In Rwanda, three coffee cooperatives conducted trainings to educate farmers on violence against women. There was a reported increase in the questioning of violence by men, more equitable division of labour as well as a decrease in the number of cases. Results in Rwanda are qualitative and not assessed against a control group.
The program activities show possibilities for future attitude and behaviour change inititiatives, and the four approaches share lessons in engaging and retaining large numbers of men (and women in some settings) in initiatives to address violence against women. Recommendations for future work include the need for more joint interventions promoting women?s empowerment together with engaging men, and rigorous assessment of the impact of programmes, accompanied by strong monitoring and evaluation systems.]]></description>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Men as Perpetrators and Victims of Armed Conflicts: Innovative Projects Aimed at Overcoming Male Violence.]]></title>
		<theme><![CDATA[Violence; conflict]]></theme>
		<region><![CDATA[Global]]></region>
		<date><![CDATA[March 2012]]></date>
		<authors><![CDATA[Schfer, R]]></authors>
		<publisher><![CDATA[Vienna Institute for International Dialogue and Cooperation]]></publisher>
		<uri><![CDATA[http://www.vidc.org/fileadmin/Bibliothek/DP/Nadja/VIDC_Schaefer_E_Leseversion.pdf]]></uri>
		<dcoumenttype><![CDATA[Paper]]></dcoumenttype>
		<summarylink><![CDATA[http://menandboys.ids.ac.uk/files/men-perpetrators-and-victims-armed-conflicts-innovative-projects-aimed-overcoming-male?vnc=G_joPoyRa-g0pEjvYxr9IMUwhUls0_teB-ZlFQZiSkY&vnp=3]]></summarylink>
		<description><![CDATA[What do male identities mean in situations of violence and armed conflict? And how can our understanding of them advance development and gender equity in conflict and post conflict settings?

This study examines the inclinations of many males for violence after wars. The author highlights the need for differentiated gender perspectives in order to put an end to widespread gender-specific and sexualized violence. The key factor being the inclusion of men in finding solutions and to the need to win them over so they can become agents of change.

The study uses country studies, projects and programs that have contributed to changes in behavior and attitudes among boys, adolescents and men in order to establish a framework of what works. The many concrete examples draw on experiences at local, national and international level, as well as on theme-related studies from various organizations of the United Nations and numerous non-governmental organizations.

Lastly the study will provide lessons learned from innovative men?s organizations and projects in African post-war and post-conflict countries, in particular those that attract boys and male youth.]]></description>
	</node>
	<node>
		<title><![CDATA[Boys and education in the global south: Emerging vulnerabilities and new opportunities for promoting changes in gender norms]]></title>
		<theme><![CDATA[Education, young boys]]></theme>
		<region><![CDATA[Global South]]></region>
		<date><![CDATA["Fall" 2012]]></date>
		<authors><![CDATA[Barker, G.Verma, R.Crownover, J.Segundo, M.Fonseca, V.Contreras, J.Heilman, B.Pawlak, P.]]></authors>
		<publisher><![CDATA[Men?s Studies Press]]></publisher>
		<uri><![CDATA[http://www.promundo.org.br/en/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Barker-et-al-Boys-and-Educ-in-Global-South-1.pdf]]></uri>
		<dcoumenttype><![CDATA[Paper]]></dcoumenttype>
		<summarylink><![CDATA[http://menandboys.ids.ac.uk/files/boys-and-education-global-south-emerging-vulnerabilities-and-new-opportunities-promoting]]></summarylink>
		<description><![CDATA[What do we know about the benefits to men and women when gender equality is a critical and prioritized component of school based curriculums? This article reviews such positive outcomes by assessing the impact of structured, participatory and conscious raising education programs that promoted gender equality in school settings in Brazil, the Balkans, and India.

The authors provide a rationale to education based initiatives by reviewing the gender norms that young people learn in school settings, how school settings can be a site of gendered violence, disparities in educational opportunities and quality for boys and girls, as well as the gendered benefits to men and women?s educational attainment and retention. The authors evaluate how globally diverse educational programs led to changes in gendered norms among girls and boys as well as reduction of bullying, dating and classroom violence, and improved sexual health outcomes using both qualitative and quantitative tools for monitoring and evaluating change.

The evaluation suggests multiple benefits including the reduction of forms of gendered violence in school settings. The evidence suggests the need for approaches that recognize and target the contextualized vulnerabilities and disparities in the lives of boys and girls, as to promote critical reflection regarding gender norms among parents and communities. The authors suggest that youth positively respond to participatory processes and that teachers appreciate and use curriculums that make gender equality a focal part of school based activities.]]></description>
	</node>
</data>
